Hi everyone once again welcome to DBS you
tech myself Gaurav and through this particular
video of today we are going to understand
how you can write any text on any image
like now you are
seeing PPT in my background here there
is also an image inside it on this image I have
written text over on image here
so how can it be written here we have to
understand through open and here and I would
like to give a small example of this so
I have a photo on which I have
written that text here so now how will this text be
written what can be the patterns
what can be the ways of
writing it today we are going to see all those things in
detail here so
let's take it inside our Jupyter
notebook and understand it completely there so
first of all what do I have to do here I will
need open and model
through which I will bring the image that is here
and I will give my text on it
so for that I am
going to import it here
What do we do here, we have to open the image for which
we are going to bring the image here. Now
first of all I have to bring the image.
We have to apply the tax on it.
Now how can we bring the image? For
that I will need a function here. So
I
create a ball bubble here with the name image underscore get. Then
after that cv2 yes cc tu here cc
tu dot im read function,
we are going to read out the image with the help of im read function.
Now which image have you brought
here? So if we talk about the image,
you can do any of these things. So
right now I do one thing. Here this
image.c is here, I do this thing here. Then I
tell it on its property.
What am I doing after going to the property?
Here first of all I need its address.
I copy the address
and pass on the address.
After that I want the name of this image here.
So I also do this name.
While slicing backward here, I transfer that name
also.  In this way
I have given your name with address here
completely and I pass R ahead of it.
This is my point. I have already got the image.
Now
we will first recise this image because the image is
very big and it will have to be recised
here. So I will recise it.
If you do not want to recise the image, then
you cannot recise the image,
but I am going to recise the image here. So to
recise the image, I will use CC you dot here, I will use
recise here.
We are going to recise the image through recise
and what are we going to do, so I am going to take the
unders, get the image
here and recise it here. And to
recise, I will keep its with
around 500 here and
around 600 here.
Next, now our image has been recised.
Now when we go to show this image, so to show the
image, we will do it here.
CC you dot here, you have I am
Show image yes I am show I am show inside
first of all I will create a window so let's
create a window with the name of that text next
what do we have here which
image do we want to show inside it so let's do I am image dot com we will
show it from that then after that if we
want to close the image here then for that
we will have to use the wait key wait we can close it and I will
tell zero pass inside it so that
I can press any button that time which
you have here the image should be very close
dat cc tu dot to close the window we will use
destroy all windows
here to close the windows and
as soon as we run it then see the
image that I have is here now on this
image I want to write that text here so
now how will it be written just
understand it after recising the email here
now we will
need a variable here which will
help us in writing the text here so I am
giving the variable here here and
giving it the name of the variable txt
yes  I am giving the name of the available text here by the name of txt
and through this
inside cv2 we have put
text, what can we do through put text,
we can write text on any image
here, now inside this you have
a lot of parameters,
understand all those parameters van by van,
what are the parameters here,
like I copy all of them and
I will paste them here because
all these parameters are going to be needed here, so
let's understand these parameters
van by van here, first of all
you have the image parameter,
what are we going to do through the image parameter, our image which is the
original image, we will have to
give it here, let's see the original image type is
inside the image dot gate, so I am
looking at all the parameters one by one, we will have to
give a parameter by the name of img,
through which we will have to give our image, so
image gate I am giving it here and
next we have the text here,
what do we want to write text on it, so
as I told you earlier also on the
top of this window  On top of this,
I have to write that tab like this, then
I will give tax here, so I have
given tax here and inside the tax,
I have named it and
after writing that tab, we have org or g which
means where do you
want to keep it, means where do you want to keep the original, means this is
your window, I will
explain it to you here, for example, if we
talk about this window, inside this window, we have
a plate running at the top, right,
after this, next, this button is visible from here,
how far should the image come down from here, means, let
me talk about here, how much distance should the image be
from this point,
means,
you will see this inside the A box format ahead, here
how far will it be from you, so from
here we will need category
and secondly, we will need an axis here, so
talk about here,
inside org, first of all it will go escordinate and the
second thing will come, you will have to
give an A coordinate here, let's see the
escordinate and the A card net inside it  If we give it here, then
inside the org, I will have to
pass that cardinate here, x to
mobile, so I go here that 50
pixels come of 50 pixels, which means 50 should be on
this side for you, 50 should come down to you, so I should
see this org there,
you have font face, font face
means
how you want to keep the style of your font, you should read it, so
look, if we talk about the style of the font, then
inside the font face we have so many phone
features, in which there is font, there is
simplex font,
you will find many such points, inside this, if
you want, you can also give their numbers,
if you want, see the number or you
can do it like this, now like
I would like to name it and
inside this, like here, this duplex one,
I would like to use the font here,
so I can use this font, to
do this, cc tu dot
what will I have to put here, I will have to write this name,
font underscore hj reflex,
so I will do it here  I will call it and
after that I will do a little here haxlix
so I am
going to write here font ok and sex
and after that I am going to do duplex
so I will find
font excel you plus here this is
what I have got here my font is
found here d next we have the
skill of font means scale of font
means that what should be the size of your font here
you can see what should be your weight so
just I want here that my
original size image of yours and
here what will be made here should be 2X it should be
3X you will have to give that
so basically it should be here next
you get the color now see this see
your colors here
as I was
talking about your colors from the beginning that what is your
color here is RGPV
color inside which see your color
combination this time here what is
your BG  In R format, yes inside this
you have bugger format, that means
first I have blue, then green, after that
comes your red color, this is how your color
format is, now if we talk about color, then the
range of color is from zero to
250, what do
you have here, the range is
between zero to 250, whatever
competition colors, that is, whatever colors you
see, you can make those colors in these three colors,
these are the three primary colors, here
first of all there is busy A, so here
if you want red color, then you have to make all the rest
zero, your channel of red color will have to be
taken from zero to 255,
so zero means you have all zeros, by making all zeros, then your
black and white color will be made
here and if you make all of them full here,
then the white color you have here will be
made yours, so here there are two
color ranges, here friends, I will give right and black
zero and if I want to show red color, then I will
give 255 color here,
next now  You get the thickness, that
means
how much thickness do you want to give to your text here, that is the
thickness, so I want that my
thickness should be up to 3 mm.
Next you have this
line type here, line type means how should the type of
your text that is being written be, that
means you should have
a little tilde here or how should it be
in the font, you can see that,
see what field do you have inside the line type, there is
line underscore four, line under eight,
linear it is a a, so I will
tell you to do line and score 8 here,
here if you want you can do the other one as well,
for that I will have to do it
cb2 yes I will need it here and
you dot here, then after that we need the
line, so basically I will do it here
about the line and by going inside the line
I am going to do line 8 here,
this is our line type, after that
next we have bottle left origin,
now what is this water left origin
Let's understand this, the button left origin
which you are seeing here, basically
what you have is something like this that if
I take the text of your image above the image, then
this text of yours is in this way, if the text of this image has to be
reversed, that is,
its mirror image has to be made, that is, the
text that is visible here now, should be
written here from this corner point,
next if you make the water image
true here, that is, enable it,
then the color of your text here will be
shown to you here from this particular point, that is, this v will be
created with you in this way, that is, the
point of v will be taken from this point here, so let's
read it
here, so what to see, whether the option
parameter is given or not, it will not make any difference when are
true, that is, if you make it true, then the
data of the image will
start from the bottom left corner from the origin,
your stop is
starting from the left corner, that is, at the top
Yours is getting ready by going to the left corner, otherwise
what will happen is that you go to the bottom left corner, all that
means if you want to
reverse the tax that is shown here in the image, then
you can put it here,
right, so here right now what I would like to
do is pause it,
next we will have trans
inside it, I will also show you by making it true
here how you
can make it true, so right now I am making it false
and all these parameters that I have created
here,
what am I doing here, I am
going to pass on all these parameters, the put tax inside it, so
what are you doing from here, let's
copy it and inside it van
by van pass on all these things
and remove it from here because now we do
not need it, so I have
told the password here for all these things, now all these marks should be separated
because we have all these
different parameters, so I make all these
marks separators right so that we
can do it on top of it here date common
seat date mark separate and mark
option  Earn and after that
what am I doing here now, so look
I have a double script A here in
red color, like this you can
see here, now this wicket is
showing very high, I will bring it down a little, that
means I will have to bring it down on A axis,
let it come down
a little inside A axis, so to
bring it down inside A axis,
what will I do here, I will make it 60 runs, so
you still have it quite high, I have to
bring it down further, so I will make it
70 runs here, so
see, this is how it is on that you, now
what I have to do here, the bottom
left original which I had made false here, I
will make it true, that means
I will make a mirror image of an image here and
show you how you can make its mirror image,
so
what am I doing here, let me just copy it
here, yes I will just copy it
and after that I will paste it here again here,
right here, I have done this here  I pasted it on it, ok
and the images that you have written here, here the tip is
written, you can also turn on the txt from here, like
this and like you
here, ok so let's see
how can images be placed one after the other here, so
however much it is being done, I will do one and
put it inside the image data guide here so that we do not face any problem
here, ok so I put it in the text
and I turn on this txt here,
so I write
txt here and after that run it,
see this, I have the w
script here, now I can see it here, in
this way you can show the wicket here,
now I go, just below it
a reverse image should also be visible, so
let's show this reverse image here,
how will the image be displayed,
so I paste it here, now the
image that I have passed, inside this image,
I will have to turn on the previous image,
otherwise it will not be reduced with my original image,
so here I will give  Let me
put whatever is inside TXT
here and after that I will
do it here, I will make it true here
and after making it true, now I will
run it here, so see, it will
show me the top and bottom of both here, that
means it is showing me the image
but let me reduce it by one, sometimes I change the color of the image
and sometimes I change the color here, so
for now let me make it in blue scale
because it will look a little good
here, it is a little good in its red scale, it is
showing a little strange
here because we have such an image, so
I will make it 255 here and
after this I will keep it in the red image
so that it will show you depending on both,
how it shows up and down, let's run it,
look above, the blue scale has been shown below you,
now if you want, you
can bring it down inside the A axis, here to
bring it down inside the A axis, you
change it a little here, make it 80,
as you run it, now see exactly you can
also see the mirror image of the top and bottom, so
if you  Place a text,
then after this text, place a text again on top of it.
What will you see,
like a mirror image, you see the text here.
Here, if you have an image,
if you want to place a text on top of that image,
you can do it this way. Let me
tell you once again how to bring it here.
First of all, you have to read it with the IM read function. If you
want to directly recite the file, you can do it. If you don't want to, you can't.
After that,
what do you have to do? You can pass all these parameters inside the put text. Now, there are
different fonts inside it, you can do it here, you can do it
differently. Now, when it comes to its
measurement,
we mostly do it in machine learning
cases. Face detection is done inside machine learning,
through which any of your personal people,
if you want to read the face of that person, you have to
detect its details and along with it, you have to
show its name etc. on top with a square packet here.
What is that thing, what is the thing made here?  If
you want to create something like this here,
then for that you need a tax here, so
you can use this type of it there, so
what did you do here,
we saw the text one after the other,
what kind of tax has been placed on it, in this way
you have a different color, if you apply color to it, then
it appears to you like a mirror image here, so I
think I hope you must have
understood, done, I
showed you the entire code again, first we
showed you the image, then we created the tax, again
inside the tax, I wrote the second tax here
and after that we showed its image,
so I think you must have
overall understood that in this way you must have
understood the meaning of bottom origin, you have to
go from the top here, otherwise from bottom to top,
you will have an app here, so for
now, that's all for today's video,
see you with our next video,
until then you will be with us like this,
Til Den, very goodbye
[Prashant]
[Music]